ABOUT

I am an Application Developer with extensive experience working as a Full Stack developer, QA and UI/UX engineer, systems administrator. Current career goals and objectives: minimize costs and maximize performance of software solutions, continuously learn new technologies to overcome challenges and improve operational efficiency, empower and lead effective teams of engineers. Also interested in finance, markets, investments, high frequency trading, PWM, etc.

EDUCATION

Babson College Babson Park, MA

F. W. Olin Graduate School of Business

MBA GPA: 3.87

• Finance concentration, Investments track

• Business Analytics concentration

Wentworth Institute of Technology

Boston, MA

May 2016 – present

College of Engineering and Technology September 2011 – April 2014

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.82

- Dean's List (2011-2014)
- Tau Alpha Pi Honor Society, 2014 Annual Awards Recipient
- Wentworth Community Scholarship and Wentworth Merit Scholarship Recipient
- Graduated with honors: magna cum laude

University of Tyumen (transferred out)

Tyumen, Russia

Institute of Mathematics and Computer Science

September 2008 - May 2011

BS/MS in Software Development and Computer Systems Administration

GPA: 3.63

- Full Tuition Scholarship
- 2008 Outstanding Incoming Class Award Recipient

WORK EXPERIENCE

Babson College

Babson Park, MA

Application Developer

Apr 2014 – present

- Designing and developing dynamic web applications for Babson Portal in ColdFusion using Fusebox (an MVC framework for Adobe ColdFusion (ACF) / PHP), MSSQL Server, JavaScript, CSS, and HTML/XML;
- Working on development of new Babson Student Portal in ACF and PHP using Drupal;
- Developing integration solutions between a variety of systems and applications using SOAP and RESTful web services, APIs, ETL and MSSQL Server, and other tools;
- Researching, proposing, and integrating new software solutions into the Babson platform.

WORK EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED

Babson College

Babson Park, MA

Application Developer Intern

May 2012 – Apr 2014

- Writing scripts in Apache JellyScript and XML to automate services in JIRA;
- Writing REST compatible plugins and standalone gadgets for JIRA using Google Gadget API, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, OAuth and Maven, with JSON and XML feeds;
- Creating unit tests using Selenium and JUnit to validate services for a variety of systems.

The Web, Inc.

Tyumen, Russia

System Administrator, Printing Station Operator (Part Time)

- May 2008 May 2010
- Managed a small sales database (MS Access);
- Developed and supported company's website (HTML, CSS, JS);
- Learned about Internet technologies and web standards.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced knowledge of ACF, t-SQL, JS, CSS, XML/HTML, PHP, ETL tools (Informatica), JIRA and Confluence administration and others.

Intermediate knowledge of C/C#, .NET, Java, Drupal, SOAP and RESTful webservices, Salesforce (developer, admin), Workday, git.

Familiarity with most flavors of shell scripting, Assembly (MASM), Python, Perl, Objective C/Swift, Selenium, CrazyEgg, Mendix, Neoload, Laserfiche, webRTC, MEAN stack.

CONFERENCES, WORKSHOPS, AND SEMINARS ATTENDEE

- Reality VR Hack 2016 @ MIT, October 2016 (Cambridge, MA)
- AT&T Mobile App Hackathon 2016 @ Workbar, August 2016 (Boston, MA)
- AT&T WebRTC Boston Coding Workshop, May 2016 (Boston, MA)
- Future of Wearables ScrambleTM 2016 @ Babson, April 2016 (Wellelsey, MA)
- Salesforce World Tour 2016 Boston, April 2016 (Boston, MA)
- Boston Code Camp 24 and 25, November 2015 / March 2016 (Cambridge, MA)
- Workday Higher Education Summit, October 2015 (Wellesley, MA)
- Neotys North American User Conference, October 2015 (Boston, MA)
- Dyn's Hackademy, May 2015 (Manchester, NH) Result: Conversion Wars Web App
- Workday workshop, April 2015 (Wellesley, MA)
- NeoLoad 3-day training, February 2015 (Waltham, MA)
- <u>Laserfiche</u> 4-day onsite training, September 2014 (Wellesley, MA)
- Mendix 3-day onsite training, August 2014 (Wellesley, MA)
- Dyn's Hackademy, May 2014 (Manchester, NH) Result: DWC BoyScouts iOS App

VADIM MANOKHIN

https://manokhinv.github.io

(857) 999-1020

VOLUNTEER SERVICE AND ACTIVITIES

Babson Entrepreneurial Thought & Action (ET&A) Award

Selection Committee Member

Babson Park, MA

October 2016

Babson Undergraduate Commencement

Commencement Host

Babson Park, MA May 2016

Wentworth Admissions Office

Admissions Blogger

Boston, MA

January 2014 – April 2014

Wentworth Career Services

Web Application Developer

Boston, MA

May 2013 - April 2014

Wentworth International Student Services

International Student Ambassador

Boston, MA

August 2012 – April 2014

Wentworth President's Host Society

Boston, MA

President's Host

February 2012 – April 2014

- Represented the Institute at various events, on and off campus
- Served as an ambassador of public relations in various supporting roles
- Promoted Wentworth's academic programs, services and student activities

Wentworth Community Partnership

Boston, MA

Alternative Spring Break Volunteer

March 2012

- Focused on environmental work in the Biscayne and the Everglades National Parks, FL
- Worked with wounded birds at the Florida Keys Wild Bird Sanctuary, FL
- Worked with animals at Florida Monkey Forest Zoo, Key Largo, FL

Wentworth Counseling Center & Disability Services Partnership

Boston, MA

English II Note Taker for a Disabled Student

October 2011 - December 2011